<?xml version="1.0"?>

<!--
  Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one
  or more contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file
  distributed with this work for additional information
  regarding copyright ownership.  The ASF licenses this file
  to you under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the
  "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance
  with the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at

  http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
  software distributed under the License is distributed on an
  "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
  KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
  specific language governing permissions and limitations
  under the License.
-->

<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">
  <properties>
    <title>olamy resume home</title>
    <author email="olamy@apache.org">Olivier Lamy</author>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Resume">
      <p>
        You can find a resume in more administrative format <b><a href="olamy-resume.doc">.doc</a></b> or <b><a href="olamy-resume.pdf">.pdf</a></b> (it's normally up2date)
        And in French (<b><a href="olamy-resume-fr.doc">.doc</a></b>)
      </p>
      <p>As an opensource addict, I use maven to build and publish resume regarding myself :-)</p>
      <p>
        Olivier Lamy
      </p>
      <p> 
        If you need more details contact me : olamy AT apache DOT org
        <br/>
        You can find me on <a href="http://twitter.com/olamy" target="_blank">twitter</a> , <a href="http://fr.linkedin.com/in/olamy" target="_blank">linkedin</a> and some blog entries <a href="http://olamy.blogspot.com/" target="_blank">http://olamy.blogspot.com/</a>.
      </p>
      <p>This resume can change so you can have a look at the <a href="changelog.html">changelog</a></p>
      <subsection name="Work Experience">
        <p>
          <b>08/2011 - present : Open Source Architect <a href="http://www.talend.com" target="_blank">Talend</a></b>
          <br/><br/>
          Working on ASF projects : Apache Maven, Apache Archiva, etc...
        </p>
        <p>
          <b>09/2001 – 07/2011  : Technical Lead / Application Architect – Accor (Hospitality Department)</b>
          <br/><br/>
          <i>OpenTravel / XML / Interfaces :</i>
          <br/>
          <ul>
            <li>Lead Developper of an XML Inteface between The Accor Central Reservation System and some Hotel Vendors 
            (Major ones are :  
            <a href="http://www.amadeus.com" target="_blank">Amadeus</a>, 
            <a href="http://www.sabre.com" target="_blank">Sabre</a>, 
            <a href="http://www.travelport.com" target="_blank">Travelport</a>, 
            <a href="http://www.expedia.com" target="_blank">Expedia</a>, 
            <a href="http://www.booking.com" target="_blank">booking.com</a> , 
            <a href="http://www.kayak.com" target="_blank">kayak</a> etc…)</li>
            <li>Developed in Java the core architecture to have a pluggable mechanism to handle various XML format from different partners.  
            Use IOC containers technologies (Plexus, Spring).</li>
            <li>Application running as a simple webapp in the Tomcat container in Solaris system.</li>
            <li>Implements a Java application to send to various partners (Expedia, booking.com) rates and inventories in the XML/OTA format.</li>
            <li>Developed application to build XML/OTA files containing all informations regarding Accor properties 
            (<a href="http://repos.accorhotels.com/ota/index.html" target="_blank">http://repos.accorhotels.com/ota/index.html</a>)</li>
          </ul>
          <br/>
          <i>Intranet Hospitality Applications</i>
          <br/>
          <ul>
            <li>Implements the first prototype regarding migrating some 
            internal applications written in client-server to a Web Technology (Struts2/Spring/Tiles/yui).</li>
            <li>Personally standardized the architecture of the applications based on the Struts2/Spring/Tiles frameworks 
            and implements some common web based components shared in all applications.
            </li>
            <li>Architect the system for high redundancy using Apache Web Server, Apache Tomcat and network load balancing.</li>
          </ul>
          <br/>
          <i>Internal Company Web Services used by the Front End Website ( <a href="http://www.accorhotels.com" target="_blank">http://www.accorhotels.com</a> )</i>
          <br/>
          <ul>
            <li>Implements an application which dynamically execute stored procedures and exchange the result with xml.</li>
            <li>Developed a set of common web services (first version with SOAP Axis then moved to REST using jersey framework) 
            for various applications to access easily to the core system)</li>
          </ul> 
          <i>Common Components / Development Standardization</i>
          <ul>
            <li>Evangelism to use standard development tools with using Apache Maven, Subversion SCM System, Continuous Integration (Continuum , Hudson) and Sonar.</li>
            <li>Responsible for creating processes and practices to maximize software quality and productivity.</li>
            <li>Build a project “a la” Apache Commons  to share reusable Java Components (database access, common hospitality functionality) between various company departments.</li>
            <li>Implements a global crs real time transaction monitoring (gwt front, rrd storing) : 
            store/display various figures (number, response time, average response time, etc..) on transactions accessing to the Central Reservation System (load datas from applications using REST/json).</li>
            <li>Implements a global crs configuration database access configuration (gwt, spring, jpa2) to enable real time “load balancing” 
            for routing various applications to the database “grid”.</li>
            <li>Implements a cache mechanism in order to prevent applications accessing all the time to the core system 
            to get Hotel Availabilities (reduce database accesses to ~15%) (use ehcache and Woodstox xml fast parser).</li>
          </ul>
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Open Sources Experiences ">
        <p>
          <b>09/2007 – Present: Apache Member/Committer/PMC</b>
          <br/><br/>
          <i>Maven Project:</i>
          <br/>
          <ul>
            <li>Bug fixes on Maven core and various Maven plugins.</li>
            <li>Main maintainer of Maven Scm library.</li>
          </ul>
          <br/>
          <i>COntinuum Project (not anymore active in this project):</i>
          <br/>
          <ul>
            <li>Work on moving from Plexus IOC to Spring.</li>
            <li>Work on moving from velocity to Struts 2.</li>
          </ul>
          <br/>          
          <b>09/2007 – Present: : Codehaus Committer</b>
          <br/><br/>
          <i>Plexus Project :</i>
          <br/>
          <ul>
            <li>Work on plexus IOC Container.</li>
            <li>Work on some Plexus Components.</li>
          </ul>
          <br/>
          <i>Mojo Project :</i>
          <br/>
          <ul>
            <li>Work on various Maven Plugins out of the Apache Foundation.</li>
          </ul>  
          <br/>
          <i>Modello Project :</i>
          <br/>
          <ul>
            <li>Work on some bug fixes in the Maven main component.</li>
          </ul>
          <br/>
          <b>09/2007 – Present: : Jenkins (previously Hudson) Committer</b>
          <br/>
          <ul>
            <li>Implements Apache Maven 3 support and fix some issues in the Jenkins/Hudson project.</li>
          </ul>
        </p>
      </subsection> 
      <subsection name="Education">
        <p>
          <ul>
            <li>Starting DEST Software development during spare time. (not yet finished as not enough spare time to continue :-( ))</li>
            <li>DEUG Lettres Modernes (French literature).</li>
            <li>DUT Electrical Engineering and Computer Engineering.</li>
          </ul>
        </p>
      </subsection>     
    </section>
  </body>
</document>


